Abhishek Raj

Personal Portfolio:

 $\frac{https://abhishek27portfolio.github.io/P}{ortfolio.github.io/}$

rockman.abhishek27@gmail.com Mobile: 8400277463

SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with a strong background in developing award-winning strategies for a diverse clientele. 2+ years of industry experience includes leading large engineering teams to achieve concrete goals on astrict deadline. Strong skills include Low Code Development, High Code Development and SQL Database.

EDUCATION DETAILS

- 10th ICSE Board [2013] with aggregate of 86% from City Montessori School Lucknow
- 12th ISC Board [2015] with aggregate of 90% from City Montessori school Lucknow
- B.tech (COMPUTER ENGINEERING) Honors [2020] with aggregate of 71% from Arya Institute of Engineering and Technology, Jaipur

WORK EXPERIENCE

 Working as Senior Appian Developer for Xebia | Appcino Technologies from Nov 2023 to Current date Role: Senior Appian Developer

My Domian includes:

- 1. Interfaces, Process Models, Expression Rules, Integerations and other Objects available within appian.
- 2. Maria Database
- 3. Appian Portals
- 4. Appian RPA (Basic use cases)
- Working as Software Engineer in Cappemini India Pvt ltd from Apr 2021 to till date

Role: Analyst/Software Engineer A4

Worked as Infrastructure Support Engineer in Project CSL Behring (Cappemini) from Aug 2021 to Jan 2022
Role: Windows Server Administrator- L3

Initially worked on P1 & P2 and the escalated tasks only.

Technology worked on are as follows:

- 1. Active Directory
- 2. DNS
- 3. DHCP
- 4. Flexible Single master operations (FSMO)
- 5. Group Policy Management
- 6. Backup Management
- 7. Active Directory Domain Services (ADDS)
- 8. Windows Server Update Services (WSUS)
- Worked as Software Engineer in Project Automation Development Center (Capgemini) from Apr 2022 to Jun 2022

Role: Splunk Developer

Worked as Web Developer in Research design and standard organization (RDSO) from Jun 2019 to Jul 2019
Role: Intern

PROJECT DETAILS

• Project Ambition

Description: I have joined the project as Senior Appian Developer. My role was to develop

and Manage the junior resources. I work with various Tech Leads and Solution

Architects to design POC and DB Design.

Duration: Till Date

Role : Senior Appian Developer

Team Size : 1

• Project Automation Development Center

Description: I have joined as a Splunk Developer. I have been trained to make Dashboard for

capgemini internal projects to implement automation in various projects.

Duration: 3 Months

Role : Splunk Developer

Team Size : 7

CSL Bhering

Description: As part of Wintel L3, I have been working under DCS tower to support and resolve P1

and P2 incidents. Technology worked on are as follows:-

1. Active Directory

2. DNS

3. DHCP

4. Flexible Single master operations (FSMO)

5. Group Policy Management

6. Backup Management

7. Active Directory Domain Services (ADDS) 8. Windows Server Update Services (WSUS)

Duration: 6 months

Role: Windows Server Administrator- L3

Team Size : 12

Official Website of RDSO

Description: During my Internship period, I was tasked to create a fully functional website with

backend included. I have made a website by using HTML, CSS, PHP, JAVASCRIPT, MS SQL, JDBC, etc. All the basic web scripting was used and an interactive website was

made my me.

Duration: 1 Month

Role : Web Developer

DRIVER DROWNINESS DECTECTION SYSTEM

Description: This is my python project in which I used python lib like OPENCV and much more to

create a detection system for drivers working late at night. My project tells if the driver is sleepy or not by monitoring his/her eye closing duration. If the eye closes for more than 5

sec a sound of high pitch is made to alert the driver.

Duration: 1 month

Role: Python Developer

Iot and Rasberry Pi

Description: I have made a python project using rasberry Pi for door unlock using finger print.

Duration: 1 month

Role : Python developer

Android Messaging Application

Description : Using Android Studio, I developed an application for chatting purpose.

Duration: 10 Days

Role : Application Developer

FIELD OF INTEREST

- Programming
- Scripting
- Debugging
- Action and Arcade Gaming
- Horror Movies

SKILLS

- Appian
- Maria DB
- API Integerations
- Saleforce Basics
- Core Java
- Core Python
- Web development
- Windows Server
- Linux

STRENGTH & HOBBIES

- Fluent English speaking and writing skills
- Email writing
- Management
- Programming
- Penetration Testing using Kali Linux
- Website making
- Photography
- Travelling

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.